Jill Hannay INTERACTION DESIGNER

512.906.9842 info@jillhannay.com

I am a Seattle-based, multi-media designer specializing in web design, UX design, print design and branding. My goal is to bridge strategic messaging and branding with audiences through beautiful, usable design. With a background in art history and writing, and training in responsive web design, print, and branding, I am a versatile designer who is passionate about communication, culture, ethics, and aesthetics.

Experience

FELL SWOOP

Visual Designer

October 2014- present

Envisioned, designed, tested, and delivered responsive websites and interactive marketing solutions for Fortune 500 companies, including RealSimple.com, Time.com, People.com, Microsoft, *The New Yorker*, and Facebook. Collaborated with strategists, UX designers, copy writers, and front-end developers to transform in-depth user research into usable, beautiful, and responsive web solutions.

FRYE ART MUSEUM

Associate Designer September 2013 – June 2014
Designed collateral, environmental graphics, and publications for museum promotions, exhibitions, and events. Independent projects included: brochures, invitations, advertisements for print and web, exhibition materials including wall graphics, outdoor signs, and magazine layouts.

FREELANCE WORK

2011-2016 select freelance projects

Resource Equity Branding & Website Design

Website: resourceequity.org

4Culture Branding & Collateral

Date: Nov. 2014 - present Client: 4Culture/Creative Justice

Role: Art Director/Graphic Designer

Landesa Toolkit for Women's Land Rights

Date: Nov. 2014 - January 2015 Client: Landesa.org

Role: Art Director/Graphic Designer

Sur La Table Internal Marketing

Date: Aug. 2014-Nov. 2014 Client: Sur La Table

Role: Graphic Designer

Origin Magazine

Date: January 2011 - January 2012 Client: Origin Magazine

Role: Art Director Website: originmagazine.com

Education

SEATTLE CENTRAL CREATIVE ACADEMY

Graphic Design Program, Class of 2014

EVERGREEN STATE COLLEGE

Focus in Visual Studies, Bachelor of Arts, 2011

Featured Projects

NETHOPE WEBSITE REDESIGN

Role: Lead Designer Client: NetHope Website: NetHope.org

Led design planning and execution as a member of a 4-person, agile team. Created original CSS style guide, icon set, and visual designs for a custom wordpress website template. Worked closely with UX strategists and front-end developer to create an impactful and usable design.

PEOPLE MAGAZINE: SEXIEST MAN ALIVE 2015

Role: Lead Designer Client: TIME, Inc.
Created online marketing concepts for the pre- and post-reveal
of People Magazine's Sexiest Man Alive Issue, including
advertising for web and social media, and landing and checkout
pages. Who was it? David Beckham.

THE NEW YORKER SPECIAL ISSUE LANDING PAGE

Role: Lead Designer Client: Condé Nast Created unique landing pages for a series of publications produced by The New Yorker, including checkout pages and web-based promotions. Publications include: The New Yorker 90th Anniversary Book of Cartoons, The New Yorker True Crimes.

TIME.COM PAYWALL SYSTEMS

Role: Lead Designer Client: TIME, Inc. Worked closely with TIME's editorial, web and consumer marketing teams to introduce a paywall to various TIME, Inc. properties, including TIME, MONEY, InStyle, Real Simple and Cooking Light. Created a range of creative concepts to emphasize brand value and editorial breath of publication. Created placements and paywall messages for responsive application across the web.

Skills

InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, PowerPoint, InVision, Keynote, DreamWeaver, WordPress, Microsoft Office, Concepting, Sketching, Typography, Copywriting, Branding, Visual Design, Html/css/js, Responsive Web Design, UX Design, Project Management, Screen Printing, Letterpress

Contact

Jill Hannay 512.906.9842 info@jillhannay.com jillhannay.com